I hope you enjoyed implementing
希望你在迷你项目的第一部分
iterative policy evaluation in the first part of the mini project.
成功地实现了迭代策略评估
Feel free to use your algorithm to evaluate a policy for any finite MDP of your choosing.
你可以使用你的算法评估任何有限 MDP 的策略
You need not confine yourself to the Frozen Lake environment.
不一定非要使用冰冻湖泊环境
Just remember that policy evaluation
只需记住
requires the agent to have full knowledge of the MDP.
策略评估要求智能体完全了解 MDP
Then if you like, you can use the second part of
然后 你可以通过迷你项目的第二部分
the mini project to obtain the corresponding action value function.
获得相应的动作值函数
But for now, let's continue our search for an optimal policy.
现在 我们继续搜索最优策略
Policy evaluation gets us partially there.
策略评估已经使我们进一步接近最优策略
After all, in order to figure out the best policy,
毕竟 为了得出最佳策略
it helps to be able to evaluate candidate policies.
能够评估候选策略是有帮助的
In this video, you'll learn about policy improvement,
在本视频中 你将学习策略完善
an algorithm that uses the value function for a policy in
该算法使用策略的值函数
order to propose a new policy that's at least as good as the current one.
提出一个至少和当前策略一样好的新策略
But why would we want to do that?
为何要这么做呢？
Well, immediately we can see how
很快我们就会发现
policy evaluation and policy improvement could go quite nicely together.
策略评估和策略完善可以完美结合
Policy evaluation takes a policy and yields the value function.
策略评估获得一个策略并生成值函数
Then we can take that same value function and use
然后我们使用该值函数和策略完善方法
policy improvement to get a potentially new and improved policy.
获得一个潜在完善的新策略
Then it's possible to take that new policy,
然后代入该新策略
plug it in to do policy evaluation again,
再次进行策略评估
then policy improvement over and over until we converge to an optimal policy.
然后进行策略完善 不断重复下去 直到我们收敛于最优策略
Let's try to understand this better in
我们通过这节课先前阶段用到的网格示例
the context of the grid world from earlier in the lesson.
进一步了解这一过程
Remember that this was an episodic task where
注意 这是阶段性任务
the only terminal state was the bottom right hand corner.
唯一的最终状态是右下角的状态
We assume that the agent already knows everything about the environment.
我们假设智能体已经知道关于该环境的所有信息
So it knows how transitions happen and how reward is decided.
它知道变动是如何发生的以及奖励是如何确定的
And in particular, it does not need to interact
尤其是 它不需要与环境互动
with the environment to get this information,
来获得这些信息
but it still needs to determine the optimal policy.
但是它依然需要确定最优策略
So say the agent starts off with an initial guess for the optimal policy.
假设智能体先对最优策略进行初始猜测
In a previous video, we saw that it made sense to
在先前的视频中 我们发现
start with the equal probable random policy,
从对等概率随机策略开始比较合适
where in each state the agent randomly picks from a set of available actions.
在每个状态下 智能体都从一组潜在动作中随机选择一个动作
So based on this idea,
根据这一理论
the agent calculates the corresponding value function
智能体通过迭代策略评估
through iterative policy evaluation.
计算相应的值函数
We did this in an earlier video,
我们在先前的视频中完成了这一计算过程
where we saw that this was the value function.
我们发现这是值函数
So now the question becomes,
现在的问题变成
how might we design
如何设计这个策略完善步骤
this policy improvement step to find a policy that's at least as good as the current one?
以便找到至少和当前策略一样好的策略？
We'll break policy improvement into two steps.
我们将策略完善分成两个步骤
The first step is to convert the state value function to an actual value function.
第一步是将状态值函数转换成动作值函数
You've already seen how to implement this.
你已经知道如何实现这一步
And when we only follow that same procedure on this small grid world,
当我们在这个小网格环境中遵循相同的流程时
we get this action-value function.
获得了这个动作值函数
So now we need only focus on how to use
现在我们只需了解
this action-value function to obtain
如何使用这个动作值函数
a policy that's better than the equal probable random policy.
获得一个好于对等概率随机策略的策略
So here's the idea. For each state,
原理是 对于每个状态
we'll just pick the action that maximizes the action-value function.
我们将选择最大化动作值函数的动作
So beginning with the state in the top left corner,
从左上角的状态开始
one is greater than negative one,
1 大于 -1
so the policy will be to go right, instead of down.
因此该策略是向右移动 而不是向下
Then five is greater than negative one,
接着 5 大于 -1
so the policy goes down here.
因此该策略向下移动
And again, five is greater than negative one,
同样 5 大于 -1
so the policy goes right.
因此该策略向右移动
You might be wondering at this point what would happen if we encountered a state
现在你可能会疑问 如果某个状态有多个动作都能
with multiple choices of actions that maximize the action-value function.
最大化动作值函数 该怎么办
In this case you have options.
在这种情况下 你可以进行选择
You could arbitrarily pick one or construct
你可以随机选择一个动作
a stochastic policy that assigns non-zero probability to any or all of them.
或者构建一个随机性策略 为任何/所有这些动作分配非零概率
We'll go more into this soon.
稍后我们将详细讲解
But let's dig deeper into exactly why this should work.
现在深入了解为何这么做可行
Remember that the value function corresponding to a policy just stores
注意 值函数对应于当智能体在所有时间步都遵循该策略时
the expected return if the agent follows the policy for all time steps.
存储预期回报的策略
And when we calculate the action-value function,
当我们计算动作值函数时
we're looking at what would happen if the agent at some time
我们查看的是当智能体在时间步 t 选择动作 a
step t chose an action a and then henceforth followed the policy.
然后遵循该策略时会发生的情况
And our method for constructing the next policy pi_prime looks at
构建下个策略 π′的方法是
this action-value function and for each state
查看这个动作值函数 对于每个状态
determines that first action a that's best for maximizing return.
判断最适合最大化回报的第一个动作 a
In this way, it follows that whatever expected return was
这样的话 紧接着就是
associated to following the old policy pi for all time steps,
与在所有时间步遵循旧策略 π 时相关的预期回报
the agent has higher expected return If it initially
如果智能体一开始遵循策略 π′ 然后遵循策略 π
follows policy pi_prime and then henceforth follows policy pi.
预期回报将更高
That said, it's possible to prove not only
但是 有可能证明不仅在第一个时间步
is policy pi_prime better to follow for the first time step,
遵循策略 π′ 更好
it's also better to follow for all time steps.
而且在所有时间步遵循策略 π′都更好
In other words, it's possible to prove that
换句话说 有可能证明
policy pi_prime is better than or equal to policy pi.
策略 π′ 好于或等同于策略 π
And remember in order to prove this,
注意 为了证明这一点
we need to show that the value function for policy pi_prime is
我们需要表示在所有状态下 策略 π′ 的值函数
greater than or equal to the value function for policy pi for all states.
都大于或等于策略 π 的值函数
If you'd like to see how to do this in more detail,
如果你想详细了解如何完成这一证明
you're encouraged to check out the optional reading in the textbook.
建议你参阅教科书中的课外资料
For now we can plug this into our algorithm for policy improvement where as you can see,
现在我们将这一步代入策略完善算法中
the idea is that you'll first calculate
可以看出 原理是
the action-value function from the state value function.
首先根据状态值函数计算动作值函数
Then, in order to construct a better policy for each state,
然后为了为每个状态构建更好的策略
we just need to pick one action that maximizes the action-value function.
我们只需选择一个最大化动作值函数的动作
You'll have the chance to implement this algorithm yourself soon.
很快你将有机会自己实现该算法